So now you know, where fragments are used and
where we're going to use them in our app. You're
probably starting to ask, why use fragments at all?
If we want to group UI components, couldn't we just create
a View Group or maybe a re-usable XML layout
definition? Yes. But, the real power in fragments goes
beyond grouping UI elements. They allow us to fully
modularize our activities, including the life cycle events they receive
in the app state that they maintain. Fragments were
first introduced in Honeycomb to solve a particular problem. Honeycomb
was the first Android release to support tablets, and
it turned out, the best way for most apps to
create a great tablet UI. Is put two or
more, of their phone activities alongside each other. For example,
if you had a phone app that started with a
list activity like this, which you then clicked an item
would open a detailed activity like this one. What
we call a master detail flow. A good tablet
UI would put them side by side like this.
Functionally, clicking an item on this list, now replaces this
activity on the right, rather than starting a new
one, as it would have done on the phone.
Now unfortunately, Android didn't always support embedding activities within
other activities. At least, it didn't until we introduced fragments.
Now if you just look at the UI elements, you could
be excused for thinking you could achieve much the same thing
using an activity that was built using U Groups and layouts,
without bothering the fragments, which is true up to a point.
But then you'd have to pass through all of the activity
life cycle events, manage the state of each piece of the
UI, keep track of the state of each of the portions
as they changed. And remember, which screen elements were on screen
at any given time, in order to maintain app state.
All of which, is exactly what the Fragment Manager does
for you, when you use Fragments. And that lets you
take a step back and, and treat each fragment as though
it were a mini activity. For example, in the world
of activities, you start one activity from the other, and that
transaction is recorded on the back stack. So, hitting the
Back button, we'll undo that transaction and bring the first activity
to the front. Now the same thing can
happen with fragment transactions. In this case, rather
than starting a new activity, we simply replace
the list fragment with the detail fragment. And then
the back button will undo that transaction and
reverse it. So in theory, you can really take
any act with multiple activities and replace it
with a single activity that's host to multiple fragments.